<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SameSite Cookies on XS-Leaks Wiki</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/defenses/samesite-cookies/</link><description>Recent content in SameSite Cookies on XS-Leaks Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xsleaks.dev/defenses/samesite-cookies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>XS-Search</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/xs-search/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/xs-search/</guid><description>Cross-site search (XS-Search) is an important attack principle in the family of XS-Leaks. This type of attack abuses Query-Based Search Systems to leak user information from an attacker origin 1 2. The original attack uses timing measurements to detect whether or not a search system returns results and works as follows:
Establish a baseline of the time needed for a request to return results (hit), and a baseline for the time needed by a request with no results (miss).</description></item><item><title>Window References</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/window-references/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/window-references/</guid><description>If a page sets its opener property to null or is using COOP protection depending on the users' state, it becomes possible to infer cross-site information about that state. For example, attackers can detect whether a user is logged in by opening an endpoint in an iframe (or a new window) which only authenticated users have access to, simply by checking its window reference.
Code Snippet # The below snippet demonstrates how to detect whether the opener property was set to null, or whether the COOP header is present with a value other than unsafe-none.</description></item><item><title>CORB Leaks</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/browser-features/corb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/browser-features/corb/</guid><description>Cross-Origin Read Blocking (CORB) is a web platform security feature aimed at reducing the impact of speculative side-channel attacks such as Spectre. Unfortunately, blocking certain types of requests introduced a new type of XS-Leaks 1 that allows attackers to detect if CORB was enforced on one request, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t on another. Nevertheless, the introduced XS-Leaks are much less problematic than the issues actively protected by CORB (e.g. Spectre).
info</description></item><item><title>CORP Leaks</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/browser-features/corp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/browser-features/corp/</guid><description>Explanation # Cross-Origin Resource Policy (CORP) is a web platform security feature that allows websites to prevent certain resources from being loaded by other origins. This protection complements CORB since it is an opt-in defense, whereas CORB blocks some cross-origin reads by default. Unfortunately, similar to CORB, applications can introduce a new XS-Leak if they misconfigure the use of this protection.
A webpage will introduce an XS-Leak if CORP is enforced based on user data.</description></item><item><title>Error Events</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/error-events/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/error-events/</guid><description>When a webpage issues a request to a server (e.g. fetch, HTML tags), the server receives and processes this request. When received, the server decides whether the request should succeed (e.g. 200) or fail (e.g. 404) based on the provided context. When a response has an error status, an error event is fired by the browser for the page to handle. These errors also cover situations where the parser fails, for example when trying to embed HTML content as an image.</description></item><item><title>Frame Counting</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/frame-counting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/frame-counting/</guid><description>Window references allow cross-origin pages to get access to some of the attributes of other pages. These references become available when using or allowing iframe and window.open. The references provide (limited) information about the window as they still respect the same-origin policy.
One of the accessible attributes is window.length which provides the number of frames in the window. This attribute can provide valuable information about a page to an attacker.</description></item><item><title>Navigations</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/navigations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/navigations/</guid><description>Detecting if a cross-site page triggered a navigation (or didn&amp;rsquo;t) can be useful to an attacker. For example, a website may trigger a navigation in a certain endpoint depending on the status of the user.
To detect if any kind of navigation occurred, an attacker can:
Use an iframe and count the number of times the onload event is triggered. Check the value of history.length, which is accessible through any window reference.</description></item><item><title>Network Timing</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/timing-attacks/network-timing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/timing-attacks/network-timing/</guid><description>Network Timing side-channels have been present on the web since its inception 1 2. These attacks have had different levels of impact over time, gaining new attention when browsers started shipping high-precision timers like performance.now().
To obtain timing measurements, attackers must use a clock, either an implicit or an explicit one. These clocks are usually interchangeable for the purposes of XS-Leaks and only vary in accuracy and availability. For simplicity, this article assumes the use of the performance.</description></item><item><title>Cache Probing</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/cache-probing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/cache-probing/</guid><description>The principle of Cache Probing consists of detecting whether a resource was cached by the browser. The concept has been known since the beginning of the web 1 and initially relied on detecting timing differences.
When a user visits a website, some resources such as images, scripts, and HTML content are fetched and later cached by the browser (under certain conditions). This optimization makes future navigations faster as the browser serves those resources from disk instead of requesting them again.</description></item><item><title>Execution Timing</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/timing-attacks/execution-timing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/timing-attacks/execution-timing/</guid><description>Measuring the time of JavaScript execution in a browser can give attackers information on when certain events are triggered, and how long some operations take.
Timing the Event Loop # JavaScript&amp;rsquo;s concurrency model is based on a single-threaded event loop which means it can only run one task at a time. If, for example, some time-consuming task blocks the event loop, the user can perceive a freeze on a page as a result of the UI thread being starved.</description></item><item><title>Hybrid Timing</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/timing-attacks/hybrid-timing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/timing-attacks/hybrid-timing/</guid><description>Hybrid Timing Attacks allow attackers to measure the sum of a group of factors that influence the final timing measurement. These factors include:
Network delays Document parsing Retrieval and processing of subresources Code execution Some of the factors differ in value depending on the application. This means that Network Timing might be more significant for pages with more backend processing, while Execution Timing can be more significant in applications processing and displaying data within the browser.</description></item><item><title>ID Attribute</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/id-attribute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/id-attribute/</guid><description>The id attribute is widely used to identify HTML elements. Unfortunately, cross-origin websites can determine whether a given id is set anywhere on a page by leveraging the focus event and URL fragments. If https://example.com/foo#bar is loaded, the browser attempts to scroll to the element with id=&amp;quot;bar&amp;quot;. This can be detected cross-origin by loading https://example.com/foo#bar in an iframe; if there is an element with id=&amp;quot;bar&amp;quot;, the focus event fires. The blur event can also be used for the same purpose 1.</description></item><item><title>Connection Pool</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/timing-attacks/connection-pool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/timing-attacks/connection-pool/</guid><description>Another way to measure the network timing of a request consists of abusing the socket pool of a browser 1. Browsers use sockets to communicate with servers. As the operating system and the hardware it runs on have limited resources, browsers have to impose a limit.
To exploit the existence of this limit, attackers can:
Check what the limit of the browser is, for example 256 global sockets. Block \(255\) sockets for a long period of time by performing \(255\) requests to different hosts that simply hang the connection Use the \(256^{th}\) socket by performing a request to the target page.</description></item></channel></rss>