<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Window.open on XS-Leaks Wiki</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/abuse/window.open/</link><description>Recent content in Window.open on XS-Leaks Wiki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 23:25:01 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xsleaks.dev/abuse/window.open/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Navigations</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/navigations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/navigations/</guid><description>&lt;p>Detecting if a cross-site page triggered a navigation (or didn&amp;rsquo;t) can be useful to an attacker. For example, a website may trigger a navigation in a certain endpoint &lt;a href="#case-scenarios">depending on the status of the user&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To detect if any kind of navigation occurred, an attacker can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use an &lt;code>iframe&lt;/code> and count the number of times the &lt;code>onload&lt;/code> event is triggered.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check the value of &lt;code>history.length&lt;/code>, which is accessible through any window reference. This provides the number of entries in the history of a victim that were either changed by &lt;code>history.pushState&lt;/code> or by regular navigations. To get the value of &lt;code>history.length&lt;/code>, an attacker changes the location of the window reference to the target website, then changes back to same-origin, and finally reads the value. &lt;a href="https://xsinator.com/testing.html#History%20Length%20Leak">Run demo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="download-trigger">
 Download Trigger
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#download-trigger">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When an endpoint sets the &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Content-Disposition">&lt;code>Content-Disposition: attachment&lt;/code>&lt;/a> header, it instructs the browser to download the response as an attachment instead of navigating to it. Detecting if this behavior occurred might allow attackers to leak private information if the outcome depends on the state of the victim&amp;rsquo;s account.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cache Probing</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/cache-probing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/cache-probing/</guid><description>&lt;p>The principle of Cache Probing consists of detecting whether a resource was cached by the browser. The concept has been known since the beginning of the web &lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and initially relied on detecting timing differences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a user visits a website, some resources such as images, scripts, and HTML content are fetched and later cached by the browser (under certain conditions). This optimization makes future navigations faster as the browser serves those resources from disk instead of requesting them again. If an attacker can detect which resources are cached, this information can be enough to leak whether a user accessed a specific page in the past.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>