<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Content-Type on XS-Leaks Wiki</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/abuse/content-type/</link><description>Recent content in Content-Type on XS-Leaks Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xsleaks.com/abuse/content-type/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CORB Leaks</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/browser-features/corb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/browser-features/corb/</guid><description>Cross-Origin Read Blocking (CORB) is a web platform security feature aimed at reducing the impact of speculative side-channel attacks such as Spectre. Unfortunately, blocking certain types of requests introduced a new type of XS-Leaks that allows attackers to detect if CORB was enforced on one request, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t on another. Nevertheless, the introduced XS-Leaks are much less problematic than the issues actively protected by CORB (e.g Spectre).
CORB &amp;amp; Error Events # Attackers can observe when CORB is enforced if a response returns a CORB protected Content-Type (and nosniff) with status code 2xx which results in CORB stripping the body and headers from the response.</description></item><item><title>Error Events</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/error-events/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/error-events/</guid><description>When a webpage issues a request to a server (e.g fetch, HTML tags), this request will be received and processed by that server. When received the server will decide whether the request should succeed (e.g 200) or fail (e.g 404) based on the provided context. When a response has an error status an error event will be fired by the browser for the page to handle. These errors are also extended to situations where the parser fails, for example, trying to embed HTML content as an image.</description></item><item><title>Content-Type</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/historical/content-type/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/historical/content-type/</guid><description>Leaking the Content-Type of a request could offer an attacker a new way to distinguish two requests from each other.
typeMustMatch # typeMustMatch is a boolean that reflects the typeMustMatch attribute of the object element. It ensures a certain MIME type must be enforced when loading an object verifying if the Content-Type of the resource is the same as the one provided in the object. Unfortunately, this enforcement would allow attackers to leak the Content-Type and Status Codes returned by a website 1</description></item></channel></rss>