<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>XS-Leaks Wiki</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/browser-features/</link><description>Recent content on XS-Leaks Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/browser-features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CORB Leaks</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/browser-features/corb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/browser-features/corb/</guid><description>Cross-Origin Read Blocking (CORB) is a web platform security feature aimed at reducing the impact of speculative side-channel attacks such as Spectre. Unfortunately, blocking certain types of requests introduced a new type of XS-Leaks that allows attackers to detect if CORB was enforced on one request, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t on another. Nevertheless, the introduced XS-Leaks are much less problematic than the issues actively protected by CORB (e.g Spectre).
CORB &amp;amp; Error Events # Attackers can observe when CORB is enforced if a response returns a CORB protected Content-Type (and nosniff) with status code 2xx which results in CORB stripping the body and headers from the response.</description></item><item><title>CORP Leaks</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/browser-features/corp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/attacks/browser-features/corp/</guid><description>Explanation # Cross-Origin Resource Policy (CORP) is a web platform security feature that allows websites to prevent certain resources from being loaded by other origins. This protection complements CORB since it is an opt-in defense whereas CORB blocks some cross-origin reads by default. Unfortunately, similarly to CORB applications can introduce a new XS-Leak if they misconfigure the use of this protection.
A webpage will introduce an XS-Leak if CORP is enforced based on user data.</description></item></channel></rss>