<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Application Design on XS-Leaks Wiki</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/design-protections/</link><description>Recent content in Application Design on XS-Leaks Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/design-protections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Defensive Design</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/design-protections/defensive-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/design-protections/defensive-design/</guid><description>This section should focus on defensive design techniques to prevent XS-Leaks from happening. Some ideas:
The way applications use iframes to display information based on a user query (search system) How applications use Fetch Metadata with Vary headers to prevent cache probing attacks and what problems might occur with improper deployments. Are there any drawbacks of deploying this? How to ensure all application endpoints implement certain Headers to have the same behavior across different states.</description></item><item><title>Subresource Protections</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/design-protections/subresource-protections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/design-protections/subresource-protections/</guid><description>Random tokens # One of the principles of protecting subresources is the same as protecting endpoints from CSRF attacks. The difference from CSRF protections is that in the case of XS-Leaks, GET requests are the ones usually worth protecting. To apply this protection applications can append a (cryptographically strong) pseudorandom value, unique to each request/session, to make the URL of a subresource unpredictable to an attacker. The protection can be applied to the following types of subresources:</description></item></channel></rss>