<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Application Design on XS-Leaks Wiki</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/defenses/design-protections/</link><description>Recent content in Application Design on XS-Leaks Wiki</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.1</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://xsleaks.dev/docs/defenses/design-protections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cache Protections</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/defenses/design-protections/cache-protections/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/defenses/design-protections/cache-protections/</guid><description>There are a number of different approaches applications can use to defend against cache probing-based XS-Leaks. These approaches are explained in the following sections.
Cache Protection via Cache-Control Headers # If it is acceptable to disable caching, doing so provides a strong defense against cache probing attacks. Disabling caching means that every time someone loads a resource, the resource has to be fetched again. To disable caching, set a Cache-Control: no-store header on every single response that you wish to protect.</description></item><item><title>Subresource Protections</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/defenses/design-protections/subresource-protections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/defenses/design-protections/subresource-protections/</guid><description>The fundamental idea behind designing protections for subresources is that subresources cannot be targeted by XS-Leaks if the attacker cannot make them return any user data. If implemented correctly, this approach can be a very strong defense, though it is likely to be tough to implement and could negatively impact the user experience.
tip
It can be very effective to deploy this approach on any specific resources that are known to be especially sensitive to XS-Leaks.</description></item></channel></rss>