<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Secure Defaults on XS-Leaks Wiki</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/secure-defaults/</link><description>Recent content in Secure Defaults on XS-Leaks Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/secure-defaults/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cross-Origin Read Blocking</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/secure-defaults/corb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/secure-defaults/corb/</guid><description>Cross-Origin Read Blocking (CORB) is a security mechanism that prevents attackers from loading certain cross-origin resources 1. This protection was created to defend against speculative side-channel attacks such as Spectre that allow attackers to read the memory of their own process. CORB aims to prevent attackers from loading certain sensitive cross-origin resources into an attacker controlled process. For example, if the attacker tries to load cross-origin HTML, XML, or JSON into an img tag, CORB will prevent this from happening.</description></item><item><title>Partitioned HTTP Cache</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/secure-defaults/partitioned-cache/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/secure-defaults/partitioned-cache/</guid><description>In order to defend against cache probing attacks, browsers are actively working on implementing a partitioned HTTP cache that would in essence ensure each website has a distinct cache. Since cache probing relies on the fact that browsers' HTTP cache is shared across every website, this can defend against many cache probing techniques. This is done by using tuples (either (top-frame-site, resource-url) or (top-frame-site, framing-site, resource-url)) as the cache keys to ensure the cache is partitioned by the requesting site.</description></item></channel></rss>