<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Attacks on XS-Leaks Wiki</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/</link><description>Recent content in Attacks on XS-Leaks Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>XS-Search</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/xs-search/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/xs-search/</guid><description>Cross-site search (XS-Search) is an important attack and principle in the family of XS-Leaks. The attack abuses Query-Based Search Systems to leak user information from an attacker origin 1 2. The original attack used timing measurements to detect whether or not a search system returned results and works as follows:
Establish a baseline time for a request returning results (hit) and a baseline for a request with no results (miss).</description></item><item><title>Error Events</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/error-events/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/error-events/</guid><description>When a webpage issues a request to a server (e.g. fetch, HTML tags), the server receives and processes this request. When received, the server decides whether the request should succeed (e.g. 200) or fail (e.g. 404) based on the provided context. When a response has an error status, an error event is fired by the browser for the page to handle. These errors also cover situations where the parser fails, for example when trying to embed HTML content as an image.</description></item><item><title>Frame Counting</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/frame-counting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/frame-counting/</guid><description>Window references allow cross-origin pages to get access to some of the attributes of other pages. These references become available when using or allowing iframe and window.open. The references provide (limited) information about the window as they still respect the same-origin policy.
One of the accessible attributes is window.length which provides the number of frames in the window. This attribute can provide valuable information about a page to an attacker.</description></item><item><title>Navigations</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/navigations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/navigations/</guid><description>Detecting if a cross-site page triggered a navigation (or didn&amp;rsquo;t) can be useful to an attacker. For example, a website may trigger a navigation in a certain endpoint depending on the status of the user.
To detect if any kind of navigation occurred, an attacker can:
Use an iframe and count the number of times the onload event is triggered. Check the value of history.length, which is accessible through any window reference.</description></item><item><title>Cache Probing</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/cache-probing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/cache-probing/</guid><description>The principle of Cache Probing consists of detecting whether a resource was cached by the browser. The concept has been known since the beginning of the web 1 and initially relied on detecting timing differences.
When a user visits a website, some resources such as images, scripts, and HTML content are fetched and later cached by the browser (under certain conditions). This optimization makes future navigations faster as the browser serves those resources from disk instead of requesting them again.</description></item><item><title>ID Attribute</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/id-attribute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/id-attribute/</guid><description>The id attribute is widely used to identify HTML elements. Unfortunately, cross-origin websites can determine whether a given id is set anywhere on a page by leveraging the focus event and URL fragments. If https://example.com/foo#bar is loaded, the browser attempts to scroll to the element with id=&amp;quot;bar&amp;quot;. This can be detected cross-origin by loading https://example.com/foo#bar in an iframe; if there is an element with id=&amp;quot;bar&amp;quot;, the focus event fires. The blur event can also be used for the same purpose 1.</description></item><item><title>postMessage Broadcasts</title><link>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/postmessage-broadcasts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.dev/docs/attacks/postmessage-broadcasts/</guid><description>Applications often use postMessage broadcasts to share information with other origins. Using postMessage can lead to two kinds of XS-Leaks:
Sharing sensitive messages with untrusted origins
The postMessage API supports a targetOrigin parameter that can be used to restrict which origins can receive the message. If the message contains any sensitive data, it is important to use this parameter. Leaking information based on varying content or on the presence of a broadcast</description></item></channel></rss>