<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opt-In on XS-Leaks Wiki</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/</link><description>Recent content in Opt-In on XS-Leaks Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cross-Origin-Opener-Policy</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/coop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/coop/</guid><description>A good portion of XS-Leaks has multiple alternatives to execute the same attack, some in common with each other. For instance, some XS-Leaks abuse properties of iframes to succeed which can be fully mitigated by deploying Framing Protections. However, this same group of XS-Leaks can usually be abused by other common alternatives, that need other protections. One of those alternatives consists of opening a new window with window.open, allowing attackers to gain a reference to the opened window.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Origin-Resource-Policy</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/corp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/corp/</guid><description>Cross-Origin-Resource-Policy (CORP) response header enforces Cross-Origin Read Blocking (CORB) as it provides more protection by covering more resources 1. Both protect against speculative side-channel attacks (Spectre) by preventing attackers from loading certain cross-origin resources in elements like script, img, video, etc. Unlike CORB, this protection is enforced in the browser only if an application opts into the protection. Applications can define which groups of origins (same-site, same-origin, cross-site) are allowed to read their resources.</description></item><item><title>Fetch Metadata</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/fetch-metadata/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/fetch-metadata/</guid><description>Fetch Metadata Headers are sent by browsers in every request or navigation made by a page. These Headers provide context on how every request/navigation was initiated so that applications are able to make more informed decisions on how to respond to them. This allows servers to behave differently when they detect potential attacks (e.g unexpected cross-origin requests)1. This mechanism can be very effective against cross-origin attacks like XSSI, XS-Leaks, Clickjacking, and CSRF.</description></item><item><title>Framing Protections</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/xfo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/xfo/</guid><description>A considerable number of XS-Leaks relies on some properties of frames. If an attacker is unable to embed the contents of a page as an iframe, frame, embed or object then the attack may no longer be possible. To mitigate XS-Leaks which rely on these objects, pages can forbid or select which origins can embed them. This is possible by using the X-Frame-Options Header or the CSP frame-ancestors directive.
Since a website enforcing Framing Protections can&amp;rsquo;t be embedded from an attacker origin, the website is not rendered and the JavaScript does not run.</description></item><item><title>Same-Site Cookies</title><link>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/same-site-cookies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xsleaks.com/docs/defenses/opt-in/same-site-cookies/</guid><description>Same-Site Cookies are one of the most impactful Security Mechanisms towards fixing security issues that involve cross-site requests. This mechanism allows applications to add a new attribute to cookies, forcing browsers to only append them in requests that are issued same-site 1. This type of cookies has two modes: Lax and Strict.
Lax V.s Strict # The only difference between Lax and Strict is that Lax mode allows cookies to be added to requests triggered by top-level navigations.</description></item></channel></rss>